<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<GPM profile="series">
    <FGDC_Required>
        <ISO_Theme>
            <Theme_Keyword_Theasuruas>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</Theme_Keyword_Theasuruas>
            <Theme_Keyword>boundaries</Theme_Keyword>
        </ISO_Theme>
    </FGDC_Required>
    <Identification_Information>
        <Citation>
            <Originator>U.S Department of Commerce, U.S Census Bureau, Geographic Customer Services Branch</Originator>
            <Publication_Date>201603</Publication_Date>
            <Title>  Series Information File for the 2015 Cartographic Boundary File, State-County-Census Tract-Block Group, 1:500,000</Title>
            <Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form>mapDigital</Geospatial_Data_Presentation_Form>
            <Online_Linkage>https://www2.census.gov/geo/tiger/GENZ2015/kml</Online_Linkage>
      </Citation>
      <Description>
          <Abstract>The 2015 cartographic boundary shapefiles are simplified representations of selected geographic areas from the U.S. Census Bureau's Master Address File / Topologically Integrated Geographic
                    Encoding and Referencing (MAF/TIGER) Database (MTDB). These boundary files are specifically designed for small-scale thematic mapping. When possible, generalization is performed with the intent
                    to maintain the hierarchical relationships among geographies and to maintain the alignment of geographies within a file set for a given year. Geographic areas may not align with the same areas
                    from another year. Some geographies are available as nation-based files while others are available only as state-based files.
              
                    Block Groups (BGs) are clusters of blocks within the same census tract. Each census tract contains at least one BG, and BGs are uniquely numbered within census tracts.  BGs have a valid code range
                    of 0 through 9. BGs have the same first digit of their 4-digit census block number from the same decennial census.  For example, tabulation blocks numbered 3001, 3002, 3003,.., 3999 within census
                    tract 1210.02 are also within BG 3 within that census tract.  BGs coded 0 are intended to only include water area, no land area, and they are generally in territorial seas, coastal water, and
                    Great Lakes water areas. Block groups generally contain  between 600 and 3,000 people.  A BG usually covers a contiguous area but never crosses county or census tract boundaries. They may, however,
                    cross the boundaries of other geographic entities like county subdivisions, places, urban areas, voting districts, congressional districts, and American Indian / Alaska Native / Native Hawaiian
                    areas.
          </Abstract> 
          <Purpose>These files were specifically created to support small-scale thematic mapping.  To improve the appearance of shapes at small scales, areas are represented with fewer vertices than detailed
                   TIGER/Line Shapefiles.  Cartographic boundary files take up less disk space than their ungeneralized counterparts.  Cartographic boundary files take less time to render on screen than TIGER/Line
                   Shapefiles.  You can join this file with table data downloaded from American FactFinder by using the AFFGEOID field in the cartographic boundary file.  If detailed boundaries are required, please
                   use the TIGER/Line Shapefiles instead of the generalized cartographic boundary files.
          </Purpose>
      </Description>
        <Time_Period_of_Content>
            <Range_Of_Dates>
                <Beginning_Date>201603</Beginning_Date>
            <Ending_Date>201603</Ending_Date>
            </Range_Of_Dates>
            <Currentness_Reference>publication date</Currentness_Reference>
        </Time_Period_of_Content>
        <Status>
            <Progress>Completed</Progress>
            <Maintenance_and_Update_Frequency>notPlanned</Maintenance_and_Update_Frequency>
        </Status>
        <Spatial_Domain>
            <Bounding_Coordinates>
                <West_Bounding_Coordinate>-88.473227</West_Bounding_Coordinate>
                <East_Bounding_Coordinate>-84.88908</East_Bounding_Coordinate>
                <North_Bounding_Coordinate>35.008028</North_Bounding_Coordinate>
                <South_Bounding_Coordinate>30.223334</South_Bounding_Coordinate>
            </Bounding_Coordinates>
        </Spatial_Domain>
        <Keywords>
            <Theme>
                <Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus>None</Theme_Keyword_Thesaurus>
                <Theme_Keyword>2015</Theme_Keyword>
                <Theme_Keyword>KML</Theme_Keyword>
                <Theme_Keyword>Block Group</Theme_Keyword>
                <Theme_Keyword>Cartographic Boundary</Theme_Keyword>
                <Theme_Keyword>Census Tract</Theme_Keyword>
                <Theme_Keyword>County</Theme_Keyword>
                <Theme_Keyword>Generalized</Theme_Keyword>
                <Theme_Keyword></Theme_Keyword>
                <Theme_Keyword>State</Theme_Keyword>
            </Theme>
            <Place>
                <Place_Keyword_Thesaurus>National Standard Codes (ANSI INCITS 38-2009), Federal Information Processing Series (FIPS) – States/State Equivalents</Place_Keyword_Thesaurus>
                <Place_Keyword>U.S</Place_Keyword>
                <Place_Keyword>United States</Place_Keyword>
                <Place_Keyword>State or Equivalent Entity</Place_Keyword>
            </Place>
        </Keywords>
        <Constraints>
            <Access_Constraints>unrestricted</Access_Constraints>
            <Use_Constraints>copyright</Use_Constraints>
            <Use_Constraints>otherRestrictions</Use_Constraints>
            <Other_Constraints>
                Use Constraints:The intended display scale for this file is 1:500,000.  This file should not be displayed at scales larger than
                1:500,000.
                
                These products are free to use in a product or publication, however acknowledgement must be given to the U.S. Census Bureau as
                the source.  The boundary information is for visual display at appropriate small scales only.  Cartographic boundary files
                should not be used for geographic analysis including area or perimeter calculation.  Files should not be used for geocoding
                addresses.  Files should not be used for determining precise geographic area relationships.
            </Other_Constraints>
        </Constraints>
        <Point_of_Contact>
            <Contact_Organization> U.S. Department of Commerce, U.S. Census Bureau, Geography Division</Contact_Organization>
            <Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address>geo.geography@census.gov</Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address>
        </Point_of_Contact>
    </Identification_Information>
    <Distribution_Information>
        <Point_of_Contact>
            <Contact_Organization>U.S. Department of Commerce, U.S. Census Bureau, Geography Division, Spatial Data Collection and Products Branch</Contact_Organization>
            <Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address>geo.geography@census.gov</Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address>
        </Point_of_Contact>
        <Distribution_Liability>The TIGER/Line shapefiles contain geographic data only and do not
            include display mapping software or statistical data. For information on how to use the
            TIGER/Line shapefile data with specific software package users shall contact the company
            that produced the software.</Distribution_Liability>
        <Standard_Order_Process>
            <Digital_Form> 
                <Format_Name>HTML</Format_Name>
                <Format_Version_Date>2000</Format_Version_Date>
                <File_Decompression_Technique>none</File_Decompression_Technique>
                <Network_Address>
                <Network_Resource_Name>https://www.census.gov/geo/maps-data/data/cbf/cbf_blkgrp.html</Network_Resource_Name>
                    <mimeType>text/html</mimeType>
                </Network_Address>
                
            </Digital_Form> 
            <Digital_Form> 
                <Format_Name>HTML</Format_Name>
                <Format_Version_Date>2000</Format_Version_Date>
                <File_Decompression_Technique>ZIP</File_Decompression_Technique>
                <Network_Address>
                <Network_Resource_Name>https://www.census.gov/geo/maps-data/data/tiger-cart-boundary.html</Network_Resource_Name>
                    <mimeType>text/html</mimeType>
                </Network_Address>
            </Digital_Form> 
            <Digital_Form> 
                <Format_Name>HTML</Format_Name>
                <Format_Version_Date>2000</Format_Version_Date>
                <File_Decompression_Technique>ZIP</File_Decompression_Technique>
                <Network_Address>
                <Network_Resource_Name>https://meta.geo.census.gov/data/existing/decennial/GEO/CPMB/boundary/2016gz/bg_500/cb_2015_bg_500k.shp.ea.iso.xml</Network_Resource_Name>
                    <mimeType>text/xml</mimeType>
                </Network_Address>
            </Digital_Form> 
            <Fees>The online cartographic boundary files may be downloaded without charge.</Fees>
            <Ordering_Instructions>To obtain more information about ordering Cartographic Boundary Files visit https://www.census.gov/geo/www/tiger.</Ordering_Instructions>
        </Standard_Order_Process>
        <Technical_Prerequisites>The cartographic boundary files contain geographic data only and do not include display mapping software or statistical data. 
            For information on how to use cartographic boundary file data with specific software package users shall contact the company that
            produced the software.</Technical_Prerequisites>
    </Distribution_Information>
    <Metadata_Reference_Information>
        <Metadata_Date>201603</Metadata_Date>
        <Metadata_Hierarchy_Level>series</Metadata_Hierarchy_Level>
               <Point_of_Contact>
            <Contact_Organization>U.S. Department of Commerce, U.S. Census Bureau, Geography Division, Geographic Products Branch</Contact_Organization>
            <Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address>geo.geography@census.gov</Contact_Electronic_Mail_Address>
        </Point_of_Contact>
        <Metadata_Standard_Name>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</Metadata_Standard_Name>
        <Metadata_Standard_Version>FGDC-STD-001-1998</Metadata_Standard_Version>
        <Metadata_Character_Set>UTF-8</Metadata_Character_Set>
        <Metadata_File_Identifier>SampleSeriesInfo.xml</Metadata_File_Identifier>
        <Metadata_Language>eng</Metadata_Language>
    </Metadata_Reference_Information>
</GPM>